Put on a happy face.
Joker is a crime, thriller, drama film directed by Todd Phillips.
During the 1980s, a failed stand-up comedian is driven insane and turns to a life of crime
and chaos in Gotham City while becoming an infamous psychopathic crime figure.
Arthur Fleck, played by Joaquin Phoenix.
Murray Franklin, played by Robert De Niro.
Sophie Dumond, played by Zazie Beetz.
Penny Fleck, played by Frances Conroy.
Thomas Wayne, played by Brett Cullen.
Detective Burke, played by Shea Whigham.
Joker is a 2019 American psychological thriller film directed by Todd
Phillips from a screenplay he co-wrote with Scott Silver.
Based on DC Comics characters, it stars Joaquin Phoenix and
provides an alternative origin story for the Joker.
Against the backdrop of a decaying Gotham City, the film follows Arthur Fleck, a struggling mentally ill clown and aspiring
stand-up comedian whose descent into moral nihilism inspires a violent countercultural revolution against the wealthy.
The supporting cast includes Robert De Niro, Zazie Beetz, and Frances Conroy.
Phillips conceived Joker in 2016 and wrote the
script with Silver throughout 2017.
The two were inspired by 1970s character studies and the films of Martin Scorsese, particularly Taxi Driver
(1976) and The King of Comedy (1982); Scorsese was initially attached to the project as a producer.
The film loosely adapts plot elements from Batman: The Killing Joke (1988) and The Dark Knight Returns (1986), but Phillips and Silver otherwise
did not look to specific comics for inspiration, nor did they wish for it to be connected to any prior Batman film continuity.
Phoenix became attached in February 2018 and was cast that July,
while the majority of the cast signed on by August.
Principal photography took place in New York City, Jersey City
and Newark, from September to December 2018.
Joker is the first live-action theatrical Batman film to receive
an R rating from the Motion Picture Association.
Joker premiered at the 76th Venice International Film Festival on August 31, 2019 where it won the
Golden Lion, and was theatrically released in the United States on October 4 by Warner Bros.
It received mixed reviews from critics and was a box office success, setting records for an October release
and going on to gross over $1 billion worldwide, becoming the first R-rated film to do so.
It held the record for highest-grossing R-rated film until
being surpassed by Deadpool & Wolverine in 2024.
It was also the sixth-highest-grossing film of 2019
and received numerous accolades.
A sequel, Joker: Folie à Deux, was released in 2024,
to critical and commercial failure.
The film explores themes of dreams, street gang, society, psychopath, clown.
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and intense.